<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-11-30T22:21:42+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal website of Marc Girons Lopez
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Happily Ever After</title><link href="/blog/2016/happily_ever_after/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happily Ever After" /><published>2016-09-29T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-09-29T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2016/happily_ever_after</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016/happily_ever_after/"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks the point when my PhD thesis is made public ahead of the public defence. After a long period in the making it is finally available <a href="https://uu.diva-portal.org/smash/record.jsf?faces-redirect=true&amp;aq2=%5B%5B%5D%5D&amp;af=%5B%5D&amp;searchType=SIMPLE&amp;query=&amp;language=en&amp;pid=diva2%3A957429&amp;aq=%5B%5B%7B%22personId%22%3A%22margi345+OR+0000-0002-0835-8897%22%7D%5D%5D&amp;sf=all&amp;aqe=%5B%5D&amp;sortOrder=author_sort_asc&amp;onlyFullText=false&amp;noOfRows=50&amp;dswid=-3723" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>The cover image shows the junction of two rivers, which represents the merging of different disciplines to advance the knowledge on water management.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0">
        <img class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" src="/assets/img/thesis_front.jpg" alt="" title="PhD thesis" />
    </div>
</div>

<p> </p>

<p>The public defence will take place on Thursday 20 October 2016 in Hambergsalen, Geocentrum (Uppsala). Welcome!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks the point when my PhD thesis is made public ahead of the public defence. After a long period in the making it is finally available here. The cover image shows the junction of two rivers, which represents the merging of different disciplines to advance the knowledge on water management.   The public defence will take place on Thursday 20 October 2016 in Hambergsalen, Geocentrum (Uppsala). Welcome!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Rocks and Cows</title><link href="/blog/2016/on_rocks_and_cows/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Rocks and Cows" /><published>2016-06-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-06-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2016/on_rocks_and_cows</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016/on_rocks_and_cows/"><![CDATA[<p>Two weeks ago I visited the country of cows, chocolate, and clocks in order to attend the <a href="https://interpraevent2016.ch/" target="_blank">13th Congress INTERPRAEVENT</a>, which took place in Lucerne. It was a conference focusing on natural disasters in the Alpine area and therefore, in addition to floods, there was a large focus on rockfalls and avalanches. It’s always interesting to get to know what other people do!</p>

<p>I was myself presenting a poster on a new manuscript relating social memory of past flood events with the efficiency of flood warning systems, which is now submitted for publication.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Two weeks ago I visited the country of cows, chocolate, and clocks in order to attend the 13th Congress INTERPRAEVENT, which took place in Lucerne. It was a conference focusing on natural disasters in the Alpine area and therefore, in addition to floods, there was a large focus on rockfalls and avalanches. It’s always interesting to get to know what other people do! I was myself presenting a poster on a new manuscript relating social memory of past flood events with the efficiency of flood warning systems, which is now submitted for publication.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EGU reloaded</title><link href="/blog/2016/egu_reloaded/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EGU reloaded" /><published>2016-04-25T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-04-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/blog/2016/egu_reloaded</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016/egu_reloaded/"><![CDATA[<p>This year was the first that I attended the EGU General Assembly. At first I was a bit skeptical as I had been told that the conference was so big that it was easy to loose focus and get lost in the frenzy surrounding everything. Also, checking the programme it was clear that it would be impossible to attend all the interesting talks and sessions. This was the state of mind with which I went to Vienna.</p>

<p>After coming back I can say that the conference exceeded my expectations! Apart from the regular sessions - which were very interesting - there was a bunch of outreach, early career, and pedagogic session that made the experience even more enriching. In addition I could talk to a lot of people and get some pretty nice feedback on my poster.</p>

<p>Oh! And I was one of the winners of the <a href="https://blogs.egu.eu/geolog/2016/04/22/announcing-the-winners-of-the-egu-photo-contest-2016/" target="_blank">EGU Photo Contest</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year was the first that I attended the EGU General Assembly. At first I was a bit skeptical as I had been told that the conference was so big that it was easy to loose focus and get lost in the frenzy surrounding everything. Also, checking the programme it was clear that it would be impossible to attend all the interesting talks and sessions. This was the state of mind with which I went to Vienna. After coming back I can say that the conference exceeded my expectations! Apart from the regular sessions - which were very interesting - there was a bunch of outreach, early career, and pedagogic session that made the experience even more enriching. In addition I could talk to a lot of people and get some pretty nice feedback on my poster. Oh! And I was one of the winners of the EGU Photo Contest!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EGU and photo contest</title><link href="/blog/2016/egu_and_photo_contest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EGU and photo contest" /><published>2016-03-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-03-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2016/egu_and_photo_contest</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016/egu_and_photo_contest/"><![CDATA[<p>This spring I will be going to the EGU conference in Vienna, Austria. I will be presenting some of my <a href="https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2016/EGU2016-15179.pdf" target="_blank">recent work</a> on the effect of risk awareness on the efficiency of early warning systems for natural disasters.</p>

<p>But that is not all! I am also participating in the EGU Photo Contest with some <a href="https://imaggeo.egu.eu/user/m.girons/" target="_blank">pictures</a> of my trips. The photo “Living flows” has been selected as one of the finalist images and it will be exhibited during the conference:</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0">
        <img class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" src="/assets/img/living_flows.jpg" alt="" title="Living flows" />
    </div>
</div>
<div class="caption">
    Living flows
</div>

<p>There you will be able to vote for it if you like it!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This spring I will be going to the EGU conference in Vienna, Austria. I will be presenting some of my recent work on the effect of risk awareness on the efficiency of early warning systems for natural disasters. But that is not all! I am also participating in the EGU Photo Contest with some pictures of my trips. The photo “Living flows” has been selected as one of the finalist images and it will be exhibited during the conference: Living flows There you will be able to vote for it if you like it!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The website is up and rolling!</title><link href="/blog/2016/the_website_is_up_and_rolling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The website is up and rolling!" /><published>2016-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/blog/2016/the_website_is_up_and_rolling</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016/the_website_is_up_and_rolling/"><![CDATA[<p>Finally putting up a personal site. It is powered by <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/" target="_blank">Jekyll</a> and it uses <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown" target="_blank">Markdown</a> to write the posts. Piece of cake!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Finally putting up a personal site. It is powered by Jekyll and it uses Markdown to write the posts. Piece of cake!]]></summary></entry></feed>